<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>John's Notes</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://notes.johnvial.info/</id><updated>2017-05-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Vertical Video PoV by Ogilvy</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/vertical-video-pov-by-ogilvy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-12T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-12:/vertical-video-pov-by-ogilvy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Notes from &lt;a href="https://www.slideshare.net/OgilvyWW/vertical-video-pov-61386432"&gt;POV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points for Vertical Video&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zenithmedia.com/mobile-drive-19-8-increase-online-video-consumption-2016/"&gt;Zenith Optimedia&lt;/a&gt; "mobile devices will account for 58% of online watching worldwide in 2017" --&amp;gt; Although this is a press release from an ad agency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phones are kept in portrait mode 98% of the
  time
  &lt;a href="http://www.mobilemarketer.com/cms/news/video/21146.preview"&gt;(Mobile Marketer)&lt;/a&gt; although my bing search found a dead …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Notes from &lt;a href="https://www.slideshare.net/OgilvyWW/vertical-video-pov-61386432"&gt;POV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points for Vertical Video&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zenithmedia.com/mobile-drive-19-8-increase-online-video-consumption-2016/"&gt;Zenith Optimedia&lt;/a&gt; "mobile devices will account for 58% of online watching worldwide in 2017" --&amp;gt; Although this is a press release from an ad agency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phones are kept in portrait mode 98% of the
  time
  &lt;a href="http://www.mobilemarketer.com/cms/news/video/21146.preview"&gt;(Mobile Marketer)&lt;/a&gt; although my bing search found a dead link (shown above), there are lots of other people mentioning this. &lt;a href="https://gimbal.com/vertical-mobile-video-ads/"&gt;gimbal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;In 2015 29% of videos watched by Americans are done while the phone is vertical, compared with 5% in 2005.&lt;/em&gt; Lots of powerpoints, this one appears to be from the authors of the report &lt;a href="https://issuu.com/auvsi/docs/internet_trends_2015"&gt;Internet Trends 2015&lt;/a&gt; (Also in that same report, it found a 5x higher completion rate for vertical vs horizontal video ads). ("Ten years from now, when we look back at how this era of big data evolved ... we will be stunned at how uninformed we used to be when we make decisions. -- Bill Bosworth, DataStax CEO (2015)). (This trends report is actually quite valuable).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Millennials are 2x more likely to be focused on mobile video vs computer or tv video. &lt;a href="http://go.ooyala.com/rs/OOYALA/images/Ooyala-Global-Video-Index-Q4-2014.pdf"&gt;Ooyala global video index 2014&lt;/a&gt;. Report highlights included: Tables had the best video ad completion rates, while most number of video ads served was still on PC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points against vertical video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"Limited distribution [on desktop] because few other digital video sites display from that angle making it difficult to repurpose vertical content for a horizontal screen." -- attributed to Adweek but I could not find the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black Bars when watching vertical on a horizontal player.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human Visual System is designed for side to side (Attributed to WAR C, couldn't find reference).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional cost is required to make for both horizontal and vertical formats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentions the term &lt;em&gt;dark post&lt;/em&gt; in context of testing vertical and horizontal videos on a market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People 'just don't rotate their phones' [Evan Speigel, Snapchat CEO an why advertisers that have been first to test-drive arketing on the app see a reported &lt;em&gt;NINE TIMES ENGAGEENT&lt;/em&gt; when their ads are vertically oriented']&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.adweek.com/digital/heres-how-snapchats-ceo-plans-conquer-advertising-world-165339/"&gt;GARETT SLOANE, AD WEEK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brand Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;AUDI&lt;/em&gt;: an ad about AUDI's involvement in Le Mans race. Using vertical video repurposed on Snapchat. Delivered a 36% completion rate which is 80% higher than normal. (although not 9x better!). &lt;a href="http://mobilemarketingmagazine.com/audi-debuts-vertical-video-ad-format-for-le-mans/"&gt;Mobile Marketing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;TACO BELL&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;a href="http://adage.com/article/news/snapchat-live-film-introduces-taco-bell-s-locos-taco/292629/"&gt;"Rush Order"&lt;/a&gt; ad on Snapchat achieved 74M impressiosn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;VIACOM&lt;/em&gt;: For the MTV movie awards had some back-stage content not
  available on TV. The engagement was 12M, higher than the 9.8M who
  view the MTV broadcast. &lt;a href="http://variety.com/2015/digital/news/snapchat-viacom-in-pact-for-mtv-video-music-awards-exclusive-1201578838/"&gt;variety&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/business/technology/la-fi-tn-snapchat-viacom-20160209-story.html"&gt;la times&lt;/a&gt;. Used the &lt;em&gt;live stories&lt;/em&gt; feature:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Live Story is a sequence of photos and/or videos taken of a
particular event or place that are curated by Snapchat and
transmitted to its young-skewing global platform, which can drive
tens of millions of eyeballs to that footage. Live Stories have been
produced for everything from Coachella to presidential campaign
stops, and some like “VMA” are becoming sponsored plays such as a
weekly edition featuring Major League Baseball.
- variety&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that the references and links contained in this article are
very interesting. It definitely expresses a positive point of view
about the prospects for vertical video. I'm concerned that the 98% of
the time quote is from a press release, however, the results from the
Snapchat campaigns suggest that there is some merit to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How easy it is to get good engagement on other advertising platforms
such as Facebook or Youtube remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Snapchat gets crushed</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/snapchat-gets-crushed.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-11T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-11:/snapchat-gets-crushed.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Snapchat gets crushed&lt;/em&gt; that was the title of
the
&lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/10/snap-is-getting-crushed-after-falling-short-of-wall-streets-expectations/"&gt;Tech-crunch article&lt;/a&gt;. It's
main claim was that Snapchat has lost nearly all of its earnings since
it IPO'd earlier this year. Snapchat's shares are still worth $17
dollars each, I think that hardly counts as &lt;em&gt;crushed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article mentions that now …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Snapchat gets crushed&lt;/em&gt; that was the title of
the
&lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2017/05/10/snap-is-getting-crushed-after-falling-short-of-wall-streets-expectations/"&gt;Tech-crunch article&lt;/a&gt;. It's
main claim was that Snapchat has lost nearly all of its earnings since
it IPO'd earlier this year. Snapchat's shares are still worth $17
dollars each, I think that hardly counts as &lt;em&gt;crushed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article mentions that now Snapchat has IPO'd, its obliged to share
it's numbers with the stock market. Given that this has been done, and
the share's haven't plummeted to the floor, we should be able to
assume that it's not all doom and gloom for Snapchat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's fascinating to see the headline numbers for Snapchat. For
instance, it's total revenue was $149 million, and then immediately
under it there is a cost called &lt;em&gt;Cost of revenue&lt;/em&gt; $163 million. It
then goes on to have other costs, $800 Million for &lt;em&gt;research and
development&lt;/em&gt;, $200 Million for &lt;em&gt;sales and marketing&lt;/em&gt; and a ridiculous
$1.2 Billion for &lt;em&gt;General and Administrative&lt;/em&gt;. The article claims that
this last cost is due to some payouts around the IPO,
likely &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Restricted_stock"&gt;RSU's&lt;/a&gt;. I
imagine that these costs are just the costs of doing business when you
are trying to chase big advertising companies like Facebook and
Google. Still, I find the numbers incredible, and that the cost of
revenue is larger than the revenue is the most disturbing.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Wochit Can Turn Anyone Into a Video Creator</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/wochit-can-turn-anyone-into-a-video-creator.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-11T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-11:/wochit-can-turn-anyone-into-a-video-creator.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lets discuss this article &lt;a href="https://thevideoink.com/wochit-can-turn-anyone-into-a-video-creator-32ab23d262d5"&gt;wochit can turn anyone...&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It describes Wochit, a video editing tool that allows a self-service
approach to quickly creating user videos. Wochit is trying to be both
a video creation platform and a video creation distributor. They are
looking to assist small publishers in making better …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lets discuss this article &lt;a href="https://thevideoink.com/wochit-can-turn-anyone-into-a-video-creator-32ab23d262d5"&gt;wochit can turn anyone...&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It describes Wochit, a video editing tool that allows a self-service
approach to quickly creating user videos. Wochit is trying to be both
a video creation platform and a video creation distributor. They are
looking to assist small publishers in making better content, and look
to gain some share of the ad revenue from videos made using their content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that many people are starting to get fed up with YouTube, for
instance &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7LE1tR9Qo4A"&gt;H3H3&lt;/a&gt; I wonder
if there is a space for a video editor for the masses to replace the YouTube behemoth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wochit claims that you can create a video for a particular news item
within minutes of it happening. Allowing you to take advantage of breaking news. Their CEO Dror Ginzberg claims:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Most of the highly-trafficked stories get most of their traffic in the first hour,” says Ginzberg. “So if you don’t have a video there, you have to monetize it with display ads.” What Wochit pitches is the ability for you, whether you’re a publisher or a brand, to get a well-produced video out there within that time frame. “If you can have a video as soon as a story goes out, that’s a great value.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Wochit &lt;a href="https://www.wochit.com/how-it-works/"&gt;how-it-works&lt;/a&gt;
page you can see their product in use. A user types in some search
queries, chooses some video sources, and the tool appears to
automatically stitch the videos together. There is also a section that
allows the user to modify the video as well. It seems that the Wochit
service is handling the licencing of this content for the user. It
also allows the aspect ratio to be changed at the click of a button.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Getting a 10x</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/getting-a-10x.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-08T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-08:/getting-a-10x.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What approach links Jeremy Howard and Elon Musk? I recently watched Elon's &lt;a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/elon_musk_the_future_we_re_building_and_boring"&gt;interview on TEDx&lt;/a&gt;, and I've also been watching Part 2 of the Fast.AI course by Jeremy Howard, in particular, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gfhLSTkRZLI&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;lesson 9&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elon was talking about building a 10x solution to boring machines. He broke it down into …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What approach links Jeremy Howard and Elon Musk? I recently watched Elon's &lt;a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/elon_musk_the_future_we_re_building_and_boring"&gt;interview on TEDx&lt;/a&gt;, and I've also been watching Part 2 of the Fast.AI course by Jeremy Howard, in particular, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gfhLSTkRZLI&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;lesson 9&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elon was talking about building a 10x solution to boring machines. He broke it down into sub components, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boring at the front and reinforcing at the back can give a 2x speed up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of boring is proportional to the diameter of the hole, by halving the diameter we can get a 4x cost reduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By using the machine closer to it's thermal and energy limit we can get another 1.5x.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elon, then multiplied these (2x4x1.5) and claimed that it was
approximately a 10x speed improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeremy also performed a similar calculation, but instead of 10x'ing a business, he was 10x'ing computation speed. Jeremy's logic was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can use SIMD to get a 6x speed up for computation that has been
  optimized to use the SIMD instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can use Parallel processing to usally get 2-4x speed up on a standard computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeremy then claims that you can add these (6 + 4) to get a roughly 10x speed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's interesting that they disagree on how to combine the
improvement. However, they both follow a similar logical path. I think
that this is a good way to build up a 10x advantage where no
single technology can get you there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I think that you should add you multiplicatives, not multiply them, see standard algebra.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Ad Industry Sectors</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/ad-industry-sectors.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-05T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-05:/ad-industry-sectors.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is easy to be confused by the complexity of the advertising
industry. I am studying it so I can understand my future customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article will explore the high level choices that the brand
&lt;em&gt;Cowboy Binoculars&lt;/em&gt; has in advertising their product (a pair of
binoculars well suited for the …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is easy to be confused by the complexity of the advertising
industry. I am studying it so I can understand my future customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article will explore the high level choices that the brand
&lt;em&gt;Cowboy Binoculars&lt;/em&gt; has in advertising their product (a pair of
binoculars well suited for the modern cowboy). Observe Cowboy Binoculars brand below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Cowboy Binoculars" src="/images/cowboyBinoculars.png"&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In
2015
&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/gadfly/articles/2015-12-08/digital-ads-on-track-to-overtake-tv-ads-by-2017"&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt; made
predictions about the future market size of advertising industry
segments in 2017, specifically that
digital ads would overtake TV ads by 2017. A recent article
by
&lt;a href="http://adage.com/article/digital/digital-ad-revenue-surpasses-tv-desktop-iab/308808/"&gt;adage.com&lt;/a&gt; observes
that this prediction has already occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;TV Advertising&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="TV" src="/images/tv.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think of advertising, the form that most easily comes to mind
are advertisements on TV. TV holds a large share of the advertising
market, predicted at 37%. This market share has been on the decline, and a recent report by PWC suggests that TV is now primarily watched by sports fans (
&lt;a href="http://www.pwc.com/gx/en/industries/entertainment-media/outlook/segment-insights/tv-advertising.html"&gt;PWC TV Advertising Insights&lt;/a&gt; ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Print Media: Newspapers and Magazines&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Newspapers" src="/images/newspapers.png"&gt; &lt;img alt="Magazines" src="/images/magazines.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A much older form of advertising is in print media. Newspapers and
Magazines are still commonplace and are an advertising channel, yet
these forms of advertising have a very small market share, with a
predicted  9% and 4% of the advertising spend respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Radio&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Radio" src="/images/radio.png"&gt;
Radio Ads, such as traffic reports that roll into ads, have a predicted 6% of the advertising market share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Out of Home&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="outofhome" src="/images/outofhome.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An important segment that is growing is the out of home segment
(6%). This segment has a strange name but includes billboards on the
side of buildings, digital street signs on bus stops and
advertisements on taxi's and buses. A recent report by &lt;a href="https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/industries/entertainment-media/outlook/segment-insights/out-of-home-advertising.html"&gt;PWC&lt;/a&gt; includes this category in their market segment breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Digital&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Digital" src="/images/digital.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An increasingly important market segment is the Digital Advertising market. As mentioned in the introduction, it has recently supplanted TV as the largest advertising segment, having achieved &lt;a href="http://adage.com/article/digital/digital-ad-revenue-surpasses-tv-desktop-iab/308808/"&gt;38% market share&lt;/a&gt; suggests that these predictions on market share have recently been found to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital advertising includes all ads that occur through mobie phones
or computers, such as: Product recommendations on shopping sites such
as Amazon.com, Search related advertisements appearing on Google
Search, social network feed advertisements such as Facebook feed
advertisements, banner ads and pre-roll advertisements that occur
before videos on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Collecting Advertising Market Data</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/collecting_advertising_market_data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-05T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-05:/collecting_advertising_market_data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Data" src="/images/collecting_market_data.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to find articles on the internet that predict the next
movements of any particular market. I prefer to find data and conduct
my own analysis. This list is a post of sites that I think can be
useful data sources for my future analysis. Unfortunately, some data is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Data" src="/images/collecting_market_data.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to find articles on the internet that predict the next
movements of any particular market. I prefer to find data and conduct
my own analysis. This list is a post of sites that I think can be
useful data sources for my future analysis. Unfortunately, some data is behind pay walls. I hope to find free sources of data if possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://magnaglobal.com/magna-releases-us-advertising-forecast-march-2017/"&gt;Magna Global March Forecast&lt;/a&gt; I'm not sure what Magna is yet, but they appear to be publishing data, and for free too!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/272850/global-advertising-forecast/"&gt;Global Ad Expenditure (Billions)&lt;/a&gt; This site, &lt;a href="https://www.statista.com"&gt;Statista&lt;/a&gt; appears to be collecting data and sharing it for a fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/gadfly/articles/2015-12-08/digital-ads-on-track-to-overtake-tv-ads-by-2017"&gt;Digital Ads ontrack to overtake TV&lt;/a&gt; This site, which is the basis for my other post today, has some very cool charts on it, whose data I would love to have in a CSV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pwc.com/gx/en/industries/entertainment-media/outlook/segment-insights/out-of-home-advertising.html"&gt;PWC Out of home advertising&lt;/a&gt; although PWC charges for its reports, it seems to give away alot for free on this page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Max reach, view-ability and Digital &gt; TV</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/max-reach-view-ability-and-digital-tv.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-05T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-05:/max-reach-view-ability-and-digital-tv.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snapchat Homepage Takeover" src="/images/snapchat_takeover.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a combined post, where I note about some news articles I have read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Snapchat Home Page Takeover&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first article is: &lt;a href="http://marketingland.com/snap-ads-max-reach-snapchats-version-home-page-takeover-213644"&gt;Snapchat's home page takeover&lt;/a&gt;.
This article describes a new offering Snapchat is giving advertisers. The offering is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snapchat’s version guarantees that a brand’s ad will …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Snapchat Homepage Takeover" src="/images/snapchat_takeover.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a combined post, where I note about some news articles I have read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Snapchat Home Page Takeover&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first article is: &lt;a href="http://marketingland.com/snap-ads-max-reach-snapchats-version-home-page-takeover-213644"&gt;Snapchat's home page takeover&lt;/a&gt;.
This article describes a new offering Snapchat is giving advertisers. The offering is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snapchat’s version guarantees that a brand’s ad will be served to everyone in the US who is shown a Snap Ad on a given day.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found this use of &lt;em&gt;takeover&lt;/em&gt; surprising, as I had previously thought
that a site &lt;em&gt;takeover&lt;/em&gt; was a bad thing. In
my &lt;a href="http://notes.johnvial.info/digital_advertising_glossary.html"&gt;glossary post&lt;/a&gt; it's described as
when a single brand own all of the ad-slots on a particular
website. From my perspective this is inefficient use of real estate,
but I think that the terms use in mobile advertising is
different. A brand may want to have massive reach, and some kind of
guarantee that &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; will see an ad could be good for a
brand. It's interesting that something that could be seen as a bug,
actually is now a premium feature!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Ad metrics not really a thing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second article is: &lt;a href="http://www.thedrum.com/news/2017/05/03/despite-widespread-mistrust-metrics-viewability-not-really-thing-video-advertising"&gt;Ad metrics not really a thing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key point of this article is that younger executives in advertising
companies believe &lt;em&gt;viewability&lt;/em&gt; (the tracking of whether an ad was
viewed or not), to be much more important than older advertising
executives. The article goes on to suggest this is because TV was
difficult to measure, so it is considered OK for digital video to also
have poor metrics by older executives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must admit, I'm not sure what they mean by agency executives in this
case. Is this referring to the executives at advertising agencies,
brand's, some other organisations, or everyone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dangerously for digital video, 60% of the under 30's felt that video
was an ineffective medium. The article briefly mentions some terms
with regard to metrics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;good audience metrics&lt;/em&gt; 56% of executives thought this was
  important. I going to assume this means a good understanding of who
  the target audience is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;context and quality&lt;/em&gt; 62% of executives thought this was
  important. I don't understand how it is different to &lt;em&gt;good audience metrics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;GroupM&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;AVOC&lt;/em&gt; (audible and viewable on completion): were mentioned
  as "advanced" metrics in use for video ads. AVOC sounds self
  explanatory, but I'm not sure about GroupM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, the survey suggests some &lt;em&gt;offers&lt;/em&gt; that are not
successfully convincing executives to invest more on-line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;fraud-free guarantees&lt;/em&gt; A guarantee that no ad-fraud will happen?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;standardised success metrics&lt;/em&gt; Perhaps the claim that metrics are
  too difficult to understand is not really true.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;premium inventory&lt;/em&gt; I guess this is the &lt;em&gt;takeover&lt;/em&gt; option Snapchat is offering above?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survey then lists some things that would entice executives to invest more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;pricing transparency&lt;/em&gt; I wonder how we could improve this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;inventory quality&lt;/em&gt; This is related to the earlier comments on context and quality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;new formats such as vertical or 360 degree video&lt;/em&gt; Something that
  would convince 51% of executives to consider more advertising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this survey was quite interesting, I'd love to see the raw
data. Apparently it was from a company named Turn, but they are not linked on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Digital Advertising Surpasses TV&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third article for today is: &lt;a href="http://adage.com/article/digital/digital-ad-revenue-surpasses-tv-desktop-iab/308808/"&gt;Digital Advertising Surpasses TV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is actually a review of a recent IAB report, which was covered in
another article I've reviewed. So this is a review of a review!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key takeaway is that Digital Advertising is now bigger than TV,
with digital video alone having grown 53% in the last year to $9.1
Billion. Other important statistics were: mobile revenue grew by 145%
to $4.2 Billion, largely driven by mobile search, and that Digital
radio is supplanting terrestrial radio.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Understanding the advertising industry</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/understanding_the_advertising_industry.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-05T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-05:/understanding_the_advertising_industry.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;During a discussion with my co-founder we started white-boarding the
structure of the advertising industry. It turns out that its extremely
complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's try to break it down. Here is what it looks like if you want to advertise on
general websites, blogs or mobile phone apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="High level advertising structure" src="/images/ad_network_overview.png"&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That big crazy …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During a discussion with my co-founder we started white-boarding the
structure of the advertising industry. It turns out that its extremely
complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's try to break it down. Here is what it looks like if you want to advertise on
general websites, blogs or mobile phone apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="High level advertising structure" src="/images/ad_network_overview.png"&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That big crazy block in the middle is a network of large companies
that each play a role in the ecosystem. Each block can represent a
large company that excels at providing one component in the
ecosystem. From the perspective of our favourite brand, &lt;em&gt;Cowboy
Binoculars&lt;/em&gt;, it is quite complicated, and they will usually employ an
advertising agency to deal with it for them. The paths represent the
different companies that you can choose from, and the colours
represent many possible paths that could be taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this is not &lt;em&gt;Cowboy Binoculars&lt;/em&gt; only option, they could also
choose to advertise inside one of the walled gardens of the web. In
this instance the structure looks abit more like the following diagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="High level walled garden" src="/images/walled_garden_overview.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we see that there are fewer companies to deal with, as the
walled garden owner (Face-book, Google search, etc), controls the
complete chain of ad delivery. Note that &lt;em&gt;Cowboy Binoculars&lt;/em&gt; might
still employ an ad agency, and that ad agency might use other
companies, but once the ad is made it only deals with the large walled
garden provider.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Review of 5 Digital Trends at This Years New fronts</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/five_digital_trends.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-03T16:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-03T16:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-03:/five_digital_trends.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is another interesting AdTech article, again related to the New
Fronts conference that appears to be on
soon. &lt;a href="http://www.adweek.com/tv-video/5-digital-video-trends-to-watch-for-at-this-years-newfronts/"&gt;5 Digital Video Trends to Watch for at this years NewFronts&lt;/a&gt;. My
previous article is here &lt;a href="http://notes.johnvial.info/newfronts_conference.html"&gt;New Fronts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article begins with a big claim:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growth of the market for …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is another interesting AdTech article, again related to the New
Fronts conference that appears to be on
soon. &lt;a href="http://www.adweek.com/tv-video/5-digital-video-trends-to-watch-for-at-this-years-newfronts/"&gt;5 Digital Video Trends to Watch for at this years NewFronts&lt;/a&gt;. My
previous article is here &lt;a href="http://notes.johnvial.info/newfronts_conference.html"&gt;New Fronts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article begins with a big claim:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growth of the market for
    ad-supported digital video content—long form and short, scripted and
    reality based, animated and acted, for gamers, fashionistas and
    everyone in between—has skyrocketed, validating the importance of
    something that once seemed internally contradictory: an upfront
    marketplace for a theoretically limitless medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which it then tries to back up by linking to a recent
report,
&lt;a href="https://www.iab.com/news/internet-advertising-revenue-first-time-ever-total-digital-ad-spend-hits-landmark-72-5-billion-2016/"&gt;IAB Advertising Revenue Report&lt;/a&gt;. Going
to that link you are immediately punched in the face with the reports
highlights, which serves as a market size gauge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile Ad Revenue was $36.6 Billion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile Video Revenue was $4.2 Billion, 145% more than last year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link is also very cool because it has a breakdown of the market revenue's for 2015 and 2016. Very nice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, back to the 5 Digital Trends, the article has abit of fluff filler
about innovation and upstarts. It then finally delivers on the 5
digital trends we have been waiting for, although I feel more and more
like this is just a big ad for the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The five trends are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Content companies becoming data-rich.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dot point links out to the Wall Street Journal (WSJ)
link
&lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/snapchat-to-enable-ad-targeting-using-third-party-data-1484823600"&gt;Snapchat to enable ad targeting using third party data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WSJ article is basically just talking about Snapchat using
customer supermarket data to help them target their ads better. It
mentions that Facebook and Twitte are also doing it, and that they use
a program called DataLogix, which is owned by Oracle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;A machine behind the scenes in digital video.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just another point about the use of machine learning in ad
targeting. It could have been part of the previous point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Video and social go hand in hand&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This heading seems to make sense. I wonder if this is news to Ad-tech
people.  This section also references the following
article:
&lt;a href="http://www.adweek.com/digital/9-particularly-interesting-digital-marketing-stats-week-175523/"&gt;9 Particularly Interesting Marketing Stats from This Week&lt;/a&gt;.
That article also appears unremarkable, merely claiming that almost
90% of people from 20-29 use atleast one social network service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The economics of media are driven by the limited resource of user attention.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This statement is nice, and could have alot of depth, but instead it is turned into
an advertisement for the NewFronts conference, and a place to put another adweek link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;This revolution is just getting started.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, simply an ad for the NewFronts conference.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="adtech"></category></entry><entry><title>Docker Cheat Sheet</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/docker_cheat_sheet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-03T13:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-03T13:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-03:/docker_cheat_sheet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://docker.com"&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; is a very useful tool for modern web development. It allows you encapsulate a computation with the operating system and associated libraries. In principle allowing you to worry less about implicit dependencies that you have on your code, as they must made clear by the docker file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://docker.com"&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; is a very useful tool for modern web development. It allows you encapsulate a computation with the operating system and associated libraries. In principle allowing you to worry less about implicit dependencies that you have on your code, as they must made clear by the docker file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is just a list of useful commands and things to know about docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;RUN &amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; In a dockerfile, the RUN directive executes the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and then creates a new layer in the dockerfile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD [...]&lt;/code&gt; A CMD, this command is run whenever the docker image is run without any other commands. See &lt;a href="http://goinbigdata.com/docker-run-vs-cmd-vs-entrypoint/"&gt;RUN-vs-CMD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker images&lt;/code&gt; will list the images currently available in Docker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker ps&lt;/code&gt; will list the images currently running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker exec -it &amp;lt;instance_name&amp;gt; bash&lt;/code&gt; will start a bash shell inside of the docker instance name &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;instance_name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Unfortunately, this is different to the image name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker-compose up&lt;/code&gt; Assumes the presence of a docker-compose.yml file. Will run the docker container configuration described in docker-compose.yml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker-compose -f &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt; up&lt;/code&gt; run the filename &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; instead of default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker-compose up --build&lt;/code&gt; Rebulids everything described in the docker-compes.yml file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="programming"></category><category term="docker"></category></entry><entry><title>NewFronts conference</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/newfronts_conference.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-02:/newfronts_conference.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflections on the article &lt;a href="http://www.adweek.com/tv-video/as-the-newfronts-begin-6-top-execs-discuss-videos-perils-and-promises/"&gt;As the Newronts Begin, 6 Top Execs Discuss Video's Perils and Promises&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My co-founder Eric suggested that I should look at this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital video industry is just getting started, it's going to take atleast 10 years to play out and we don't know what's …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflections on the article &lt;a href="http://www.adweek.com/tv-video/as-the-newfronts-begin-6-top-execs-discuss-videos-perils-and-promises/"&gt;As the Newronts Begin, 6 Top Execs Discuss Video's Perils and Promises&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My co-founder Eric suggested that I should look at this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital video industry is just getting started, it's going to take atleast 10 years to play out and we don't know what's going to happen with regard to distribution.
- Jen Wong, President of Digital &amp;amp; COO, Time Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in terms of distribution I think Jen is referring to the big ad network providers such as facebook, snapchat, instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's clear that we need to get the metrics right... create better comparability and metrics around videos.
- Anna Bager, SVP/GM, Mobile and Video, IAB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At face value it sounds like there is alot of uncertainty about how good a particular ad product is.
I think this is a continual battle in the ad technology world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've got to have premium offerings that bring people to your brand, ... there are just too many people making content out there.
Video is where you are going to build brand equity.
- Rory Brown, President Bleacher Report&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had rarely heard the term *brand equity" before. I guess it makes sense, but I agree with Anna, it must be really hard to track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this is good and bad. It's good that so many people have created so much content that now we are drowning in content. Although, when I think about the internet that I see, I'm not sure if I agree if all the content is that good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching producers to become platform and data experts. Primarily to track the results of their stories.
- David Grant, President, PopSugar Studios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sounds reasonable. Although, I thought that the advertising industry had already internalised the need to track their ad performance using data. I wonder what I'm missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Measurement [is] underdeveloped and very imprecise ... I wish advertisers would understand that it's about the lack of technology ... it's extremely difficult and actually just favors what's happening, which is a flight back to TV.
- Jen Wong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strange, I don't understand why advertisers would choose to go back to TV because online ads are imprecisely measured. Surely TV ads are even harder? Perhaps this is just a case of "going back to what you know". Perhaps (TV ads) also means things like Netflix? Because if it's the traditional TV media, then I can't see any of those companies being around in the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can create an algorithm for to tell stories. We can create an algorithm for hits. That's just wrong, I think.
- Nick Shore, Chief Creative Strategist at Astronauts Wanted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, except that those algorithms don't work very well yet! Or atleast, they produce very &lt;a href="https://larseidnes.com/2015/10/13/auto-generating-clickbait-with-recurrent-neural-networks/"&gt;click-bait-y results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People come for the content and stay for the conversation.
- Stacy Minero, Head of planning/Creative agency at Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[when hiring for producers] You have great story-telling development and creative skills and I can teach you how to appreciate data and understand the platforms
- Nick Shore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science tools are being commoditized. You definately don't need a statistics degree to be able to understand data. I can see how this makes sense. I wonder though, have all the tools really been developed yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Shore mentions the &lt;em&gt;zeitgeist&lt;/em&gt;. He seems to be referring to the ever changing styles and tastes of modern people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is abit of excitement about VR and 360 vision in this interview. Notably Wong seems to think that 360 vision (i.e. on a phone) is a more likely thing as everyone is carry phones these days. However, the panel seems unsure how to actually create VR content well, citing that linear stories are very different to &lt;em&gt;creating worlds&lt;/em&gt;. I wonder if they will just leave it to computer game manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brands need to think about feed first. Designing content for the feed where people are more likely to scroll or swipe than they are to stop.
- Stacy Minero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting idea. Sounds like the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROI is getting in the way. I mean it's just so bloody expensive to make video.
- Nick Shore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, Nick goes on but the main point is there. There seems to be a great tension at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rory Brown thinks that &lt;a href="https://www.comscore.com/"&gt;ComScore&lt;/a&gt; (a site that measures brand performance) is getting in the way of brands. They are just optimising to increase their comscore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jen Wong thinks that &lt;a href="http://whatis.techtarget.com/definition/pre-roll-ad"&gt;preroll&lt;/a&gt; is a problem. I guess maybe because it sucks for everyone, as people try to skip as quickly as possible!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="adtech"></category></entry><entry><title>Digital Advertising Glossary</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/digital_advertising_glossary.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-01:/digital_advertising_glossary.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to understand the advertising world, the following
link helped me. &lt;a href="http://studybreakmedia.com/glossary"&gt;Advertising Glossary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've typed out many of the terms to help me remember them. Perhaps it will help you as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Tag&lt;/em&gt; Javascript that coordinates serving of ads to the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Network&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Auction Price Floor …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to understand the advertising world, the following
link helped me. &lt;a href="http://studybreakmedia.com/glossary"&gt;Advertising Glossary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've typed out many of the terms to help me remember them. Perhaps it will help you as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Tag&lt;/em&gt; Javascript that coordinates serving of ads to the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Network&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Auction Price Floor&lt;/em&gt;. I've understood that ad spots were an auction, I always thought it was one of those strange auctions that benefit the seller the most. I think it was called a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dutch_auction"&gt;Dutch Auction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creative&lt;/em&gt; Refers to a piece of work (graphic or text) that is created, I also think it could mean a person who creates that work too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daisy chain (Ad Chain)&lt;/em&gt; This term seems confusing even after having read the description. The description describes arranging ads by price, but why call it a daisy chain??&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discrepancy&lt;/em&gt; Another confusing term, I think it means the difference between the clients (viewers) and ad partners (people with ads to serve).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;DSP&lt;/em&gt; Not Digital Signal Processing, but instead Demand Side Platform, apparently a marketplace to sell ad &lt;em&gt;inventory&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;IAB&lt;/em&gt; Interactive Advertising Bureau. I guess this is a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peak_organisation"&gt;Peak Body&lt;/a&gt; for advertising industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Passback Tag&lt;/em&gt; Apparently an ad partner can choose to pass on the opportunity to serve an ad. I wonder if they still pay for the space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revenue Share Model&lt;/em&gt; Describes how much of the advertising revenue the publisher gets vs the ad provider. (The publisher is some website, the provider is an exchange like Google's Ad Exchange).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;RTB (Real Time Bidding)&lt;/em&gt; Allows advertisers to bid on ad slots in real time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;SSP (Supply Side Platform)&lt;/em&gt; Allows publishers to sell their websites inventory to sell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;View-ability&lt;/em&gt; A "new" metric, will be true if 50% of ads are displayed for atleast 1 second. I wonder how much of a problem very quickly displayed ads were for this metric to be introduced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Volume&lt;/em&gt; How many impressions or pageviews a website receives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPA (Cost Per Action)&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. the customer must take an action for the advertiser to get paid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPC (Cost Per Click)&lt;/em&gt; CPA where the action is a click.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPM (Cost Per Milli)&lt;/em&gt; Confusingly, this is per 1000 impressions, not 1e6 impressions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;eCPM (effective CPM)&lt;/em&gt; Tries to compensate for impressions that we're actually shown or paid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;rCPM (real CPM)&lt;/em&gt; A metric that takes into account the impressions that occurred. Apparently not all impressions are paid??&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ATF (Above The Fold)&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. the first part of the website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Units&lt;/em&gt; The space where an ad is displayed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Banner/Leader board, Rectangle, Tower/Skyscraper&lt;/em&gt; Terms to describe the shape of the ad unit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;BTF (Below The Fold)&lt;/em&gt; Opposite of ATF.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Native ads&lt;/em&gt; Advertising that blends into the user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rich Media&lt;/em&gt; Apparently this is richer advertising, I'm not sure I've encountered these before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rising Stars&lt;/em&gt; A "more standardised" version of Rich Media.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Site Skin&lt;/em&gt; Creative that appears behind the main content of the page. I think I've seen &lt;a href="http://www.ebay.com"&gt;e-bay&lt;/a&gt; do that before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Impression&lt;/em&gt; A single ad view, can be purchased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bounce Rate&lt;/em&gt; The percentage of users that click an ad but immediately leave the linked site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pageview&lt;/em&gt; whenever a user loads a page, a pageview occurs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Re-Targeting pixel&lt;/em&gt; A unique identifier that tracks user behaviour allowing targeted ads. It's weird that this is called a pixel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visitor&lt;/em&gt; Total count of users visiting a site. Includes multiple visits by the same person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cachebuster&lt;/em&gt; To avoid the browser caching an old ad, the source code is modified by adding a unique number for each site visit, to "bust the cache" so that the new ad is actually served.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;DMA (Designated Market Area)&lt;/em&gt; The actual geographic region that an advertiser wants to advertise in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flight&lt;/em&gt; How long the ads will run for, a time measurement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frequency Cap&lt;/em&gt; The max number of times an ad can be shown to a unique user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geo-targeting&lt;/em&gt; Seems similar to DMA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invocation code&lt;/em&gt; I think this may be synonymous with Ad Tag. Refers to the code placed on a website that "summons" an ad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Line Item&lt;/em&gt; A single unit of advertising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Order&lt;/em&gt; A group of line items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roadblock (Takeover)&lt;/em&gt; When an advertiser takes over ever available ad spot on a page, this is called a RoadBlock or Takeover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ROS (Run of Site)&lt;/em&gt; Not sure about this definition. Seems to mean that you indicate a site to have your ads run on (such as google.com).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;SOV (Share of Voice)&lt;/em&gt; The percentage of a particular advertisers inventory that an advertiser owns during a campaign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="adtech"></category></entry><entry><title>Doing Haskel Tutorial</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/haskell.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2015-04-22:/haskell.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just some from the first chapter of the online version of &lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/"&gt;Learn you a Haskell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1 Starting Out&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/starting-out"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make prompt prettier using &lt;code&gt;:set prompt "ghci&amp;gt; "&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;50 * -1&lt;/code&gt; is an error, must do `50 * (-1)'. It seems to me that this is something to do with how whatever Haskell equivalent …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just some from the first chapter of the online version of &lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/"&gt;Learn you a Haskell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1 Starting Out&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/starting-out"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make prompt prettier using &lt;code&gt;:set prompt "ghci&amp;gt; "&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;50 * -1&lt;/code&gt; is an error, must do `50 * (-1)'. It seems to me that this is something to do with how whatever Haskell equivalent of operators is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ok, so * is a function, whose arguments are but between it, its an &lt;em&gt;infix&lt;/em&gt; function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;functions are called by writing name, space, arguments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parentheses are only used to group expressions into an argument.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; is used to define functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:l&lt;/code&gt; for load to load a &lt;code&gt;.hs&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;function names cannot begin with capital letters, the character `` is ok in a function name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to define a list, use the keyword &lt;code&gt;let&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;index a list usin &lt;code&gt;!!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add to end of list with &lt;code&gt;++&lt;/code&gt; add to begining with &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt;, note that adding to end is slow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ranges done using the &lt;code&gt;..&lt;/code&gt;, i.e. &lt;code&gt;[1..20]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tuples are defined using parentheses, however they are of fixed size but can contain mixed types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list comprehensions are awesome. The &lt;code&gt;|&lt;/code&gt; defines the predicates and domains , the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/code&gt; assigns sets to a variable, and commas separate the conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="programming"></category></entry></feed>