<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>John's Notes</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://notes.johnvial.info/</id><updated>2017-05-03T16:00:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Review of 5 Digital Trends at This Years New fronts</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/five_digital_trends.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-03T16:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-03T16:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-03:/five_digital_trends.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is another interesting AdTech article, again related to the New
Fronts conference that appears to be on
soon. &lt;a href="http://www.adweek.com/tv-video/5-digital-video-trends-to-watch-for-at-this-years-newfronts/"&gt;5 Digital Video Trends to Watch for at this years NewFronts&lt;/a&gt;. My
previous article is here &lt;a href="http://notes.johnvial.info/newfronts_conference.html"&gt;New Fronts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article begins with a big claim:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growth of the market for …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is another interesting AdTech article, again related to the New
Fronts conference that appears to be on
soon. &lt;a href="http://www.adweek.com/tv-video/5-digital-video-trends-to-watch-for-at-this-years-newfronts/"&gt;5 Digital Video Trends to Watch for at this years NewFronts&lt;/a&gt;. My
previous article is here &lt;a href="http://notes.johnvial.info/newfronts_conference.html"&gt;New Fronts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article begins with a big claim:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growth of the market for
    ad-supported digital video content—long form and short, scripted and
    reality based, animated and acted, for gamers, fashionistas and
    everyone in between—has skyrocketed, validating the importance of
    something that once seemed internally contradictory: an upfront
    marketplace for a theoretically limitless medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which it then tries to back up by linking to a recent
report,
&lt;a href="https://www.iab.com/news/internet-advertising-revenue-first-time-ever-total-digital-ad-spend-hits-landmark-72-5-billion-2016/"&gt;IAB Advertising Revenue Report&lt;/a&gt;. Going
to that link you are immediately punched in the face with the reports
highlights, which serves as a market size gauge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile Ad Revenue was $36.6 Billion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile Video Revenue was $4.2 Billion, 145% more than last year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link is also very cool because it has a breakdown of the market revenue's for 2015 and 2016. Very nice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, back to the 5 Digital Trends, the article has abit of fluff filler
about innovation and upstarts. It then finally delivers on the 5
digital trends we have been waiting for, although I feel more and more
like this is just a big ad for the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The five trends are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Content companies becoming data-rich.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dot point links out to the Wall Street Journal (WSJ)
link
&lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/snapchat-to-enable-ad-targeting-using-third-party-data-1484823600"&gt;Snapchat to enable ad targeting using third party data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WSJ article is basically just talking about Snapchat using
customer supermarket data to help them target their ads better. It
mentions that Facebook and Twitte are also doing it, and that they use
a program called DataLogix, which is owned by Oracle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;A machine behind the scenes in digital video.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just another point about the use of machine learning in ad
targeting. It could have been part of the previous point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Video and social go hand in hand&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This heading seems to make sense. I wonder if this is news to Ad-tech
people.  This section also references the following
article:
&lt;a href="http://www.adweek.com/digital/9-particularly-interesting-digital-marketing-stats-week-175523/"&gt;9 Particularly Interesting Marketing Stats from This Week&lt;/a&gt;.
That article also appears unremarkable, merely claiming that almost
90% of people from 20-29 use atleast one social network service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The economics of media are driven by the limited resource of user attention.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This statement is nice, and could have alot of depth, but instead it is turned into
an advertisement for the NewFronts conference, and a place to put another adweek link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;This revolution is just getting started.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, simply an ad for the NewFronts conference.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="adtech"></category></entry><entry><title>Docker Cheat Sheet</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/docker_cheat_sheet.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-03T13:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-03T13:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-03:/docker_cheat_sheet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://docker.com"&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; is a very useful tool for modern web development. It allows you encapsulate a computation with the operating system and associated libraries. In principle allowing you to worry less about implicit dependencies that you have on your code, as they must made clear by the docker file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://docker.com"&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; is a very useful tool for modern web development. It allows you encapsulate a computation with the operating system and associated libraries. In principle allowing you to worry less about implicit dependencies that you have on your code, as they must made clear by the docker file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is just a list of useful commands and things to know about docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;RUN &amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; In a dockerfile, the RUN directive executes the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and then creates a new layer in the dockerfile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD [...]&lt;/code&gt; A CMD, this command is run whenever the docker image is run without any other commands. See &lt;a href="http://goinbigdata.com/docker-run-vs-cmd-vs-entrypoint/"&gt;RUN-vs-CMD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker images&lt;/code&gt; will list the images currently available in Docker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker ps&lt;/code&gt; will list the images currently running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker exec -it &amp;lt;instance_name&amp;gt; bash&lt;/code&gt; will start a bash shell inside of the docker instance name &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;instance_name&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Unfortunately, this is different to the image name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker-compose up&lt;/code&gt; Assumes the presence of a docker-compose.yml file. Will run the docker container configuration described in docker-compose.yml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker-compose -f &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt; up&lt;/code&gt; run the filename &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; instead of default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker-compose up --build&lt;/code&gt; Rebulids everything described in the docker-compes.yml file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="programming"></category><category term="docker"></category></entry><entry><title>NewFronts conference</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/newfronts_conference.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-02:/newfronts_conference.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflections on the article &lt;a href="http://www.adweek.com/tv-video/as-the-newfronts-begin-6-top-execs-discuss-videos-perils-and-promises/"&gt;As the Newronts Begin, 6 Top Execs Discuss Video's Perils and Promises&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My co-founder Eric suggested that I should look at this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital video industry is just getting started, it's going to take atleast 10 years to play out and we don't know what's …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflections on the article &lt;a href="http://www.adweek.com/tv-video/as-the-newfronts-begin-6-top-execs-discuss-videos-perils-and-promises/"&gt;As the Newronts Begin, 6 Top Execs Discuss Video's Perils and Promises&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My co-founder Eric suggested that I should look at this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital video industry is just getting started, it's going to take atleast 10 years to play out and we don't know what's going to happen with regard to distribution.
- Jen Wong, President of Digital &amp;amp; COO, Time Inc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in terms of distribution I think Jen is referring to the big ad network providers such as facebook, snapchat, instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's clear that we need to get the metrics right... create better comparability and metrics around videos.
- Anna Bager, SVP/GM, Mobile and Video, IAB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At face value it sounds like there is alot of uncertainty about how good a particular ad product is.
I think this is a continual battle in the ad technology world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've got to have premium offerings that bring people to your brand, ... there are just too many people making content out there.
Video is where you are going to build brand equity.
- Rory Brown, President Bleacher Report&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had rarely heard the term *brand equity" before. I guess it makes sense, but I agree with Anna, it must be really hard to track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this is good and bad. It's good that so many people have created so much content that now we are drowning in content. Although, when I think about the internet that I see, I'm not sure if I agree if all the content is that good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching producers to become platform and data experts. Primarily to track the results of their stories.
- David Grant, President, PopSugar Studios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sounds reasonable. Although, I thought that the advertising industry had already internalised the need to track their ad performance using data. I wonder what I'm missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Measurement [is] underdeveloped and very imprecise ... I wish advertisers would understand that it's about the lack of technology ... it's extremely difficult and actually just favors what's happening, which is a flight back to TV.
- Jen Wong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strange, I don't understand why advertisers would choose to go back to TV because online ads are imprecisely measured. Surely TV ads are even harder? Perhaps this is just a case of "going back to what you know". Perhaps (TV ads) also means things like Netflix? Because if it's the traditional TV media, then I can't see any of those companies being around in the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can create an algorithm for to tell stories. We can create an algorithm for hits. That's just wrong, I think.
- Nick Shore, Chief Creative Strategist at Astronauts Wanted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, except that those algorithms don't work very well yet! Or atleast, they produce very &lt;a href="https://larseidnes.com/2015/10/13/auto-generating-clickbait-with-recurrent-neural-networks/"&gt;click-bait-y results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People come for the content and stay for the conversation.
- Stacy Minero, Head of planning/Creative agency at Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[when hiring for producers] You have great story-telling development and creative skills and I can teach you how to appreciate data and understand the platforms
- Nick Shore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data science tools are being commoditized. You definately don't need a statistics degree to be able to understand data. I can see how this makes sense. I wonder though, have all the tools really been developed yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Shore mentions the &lt;em&gt;zeitgeist&lt;/em&gt;. He seems to be referring to the ever changing styles and tastes of modern people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is abit of excitement about VR and 360 vision in this interview. Notably Wong seems to think that 360 vision (i.e. on a phone) is a more likely thing as everyone is carry phones these days. However, the panel seems unsure how to actually create VR content well, citing that linear stories are very different to &lt;em&gt;creating worlds&lt;/em&gt;. I wonder if they will just leave it to computer game manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brands need to think about feed first. Designing content for the feed where people are more likely to scroll or swipe than they are to stop.
- Stacy Minero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting idea. Sounds like the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ROI is getting in the way. I mean it's just so bloody expensive to make video.
- Nick Shore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, Nick goes on but the main point is there. There seems to be a great tension at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rory Brown thinks that &lt;a href="https://www.comscore.com/"&gt;ComScore&lt;/a&gt; (a site that measures brand performance) is getting in the way of brands. They are just optimising to increase their comscore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jen Wong thinks that &lt;a href="http://whatis.techtarget.com/definition/pre-roll-ad"&gt;preroll&lt;/a&gt; is a problem. I guess maybe because it sucks for everyone, as people try to skip as quickly as possible!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="adtech"></category></entry><entry><title>Digital Advertising Glossary</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/digital_advertising_glossary.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-01:/digital_advertising_glossary.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to understand the advertising world, the following
link helped me. &lt;a href="http://studybreakmedia.com/glossary"&gt;Advertising Glossary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've typed out many of the terms to help me remember them. Perhaps it will help you as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Tag&lt;/em&gt; Javascript that coordinates serving of ads to the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Network&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Auction Price Floor …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to understand the advertising world, the following
link helped me. &lt;a href="http://studybreakmedia.com/glossary"&gt;Advertising Glossary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've typed out many of the terms to help me remember them. Perhaps it will help you as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Tag&lt;/em&gt; Javascript that coordinates serving of ads to the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Network&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Auction Price Floor&lt;/em&gt;. I've understood that ad spots were an auction, I always thought it was one of those strange auctions that benefit the seller the most. I think it was called a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dutch_auction"&gt;Dutch Auction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creative&lt;/em&gt; Refers to a piece of work (graphic or text) that is created, I also think it could mean a person who creates that work too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daisy chain (Ad Chain)&lt;/em&gt; This term seems confusing even after having read the description. The description describes arranging ads by price, but why call it a daisy chain??&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discrepancy&lt;/em&gt; Another confusing term, I think it means the difference between the clients (viewers) and ad partners (people with ads to serve).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;DSP&lt;/em&gt; Not Digital Signal Processing, but instead Demand Side Platform, apparently a marketplace to sell ad &lt;em&gt;inventory&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;IAB&lt;/em&gt; Interactive Advertising Bureau. I guess this is a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peak_organisation"&gt;Peak Body&lt;/a&gt; for advertising industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Passback Tag&lt;/em&gt; Apparently an ad partner can choose to pass on the opportunity to serve an ad. I wonder if they still pay for the space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revenue Share Model&lt;/em&gt; Describes how much of the advertising revenue the publisher gets vs the ad provider. (The publisher is some website, the provider is an exchange like Google's Ad Exchange).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;RTB (Real Time Bidding)&lt;/em&gt; Allows advertisers to bid on ad slots in real time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;SSP (Supply Side Platform)&lt;/em&gt; Allows publishers to sell their websites inventory to sell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;View-ability&lt;/em&gt; A "new" metric, will be true if 50% of ads are displayed for atleast 1 second. I wonder how much of a problem very quickly displayed ads were for this metric to be introduced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Volume&lt;/em&gt; How many impressions or pageviews a website receives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPA (Cost Per Action)&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. the customer must take an action for the advertiser to get paid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPC (Cost Per Click)&lt;/em&gt; CPA where the action is a click.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPM (Cost Per Milli)&lt;/em&gt; Confusingly, this is per 1000 impressions, not 1e6 impressions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;eCPM (effective CPM)&lt;/em&gt; Tries to compensate for impressions that we're actually shown or paid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;rCPM (real CPM)&lt;/em&gt; A metric that takes into account the impressions that occurred. Apparently not all impressions are paid??&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ATF (Above The Fold)&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. the first part of the website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Units&lt;/em&gt; The space where an ad is displayed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Banner/Leader board, Rectangle, Tower/Skyscraper&lt;/em&gt; Terms to describe the shape of the ad unit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;BTF (Below The Fold)&lt;/em&gt; Opposite of ATF.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Native ads&lt;/em&gt; Advertising that blends into the user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rich Media&lt;/em&gt; Apparently this is richer advertising, I'm not sure I've encountered these before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rising Stars&lt;/em&gt; A "more standardised" version of Rich Media.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Site Skin&lt;/em&gt; Creative that appears behind the main content of the page. I think I've seen &lt;a href="http://www.ebay.com"&gt;e-bay&lt;/a&gt; do that before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Impression&lt;/em&gt; A single ad view, can be purchased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bounce Rate&lt;/em&gt; The percentage of users that click an ad but immediately leave the linked site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pageview&lt;/em&gt; whenever a user loads a page, a pageview occurs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Re-Targeting pixel&lt;/em&gt; A unique identifier that tracks user behaviour allowing targeted ads. It's weird that this is called a pixel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visitor&lt;/em&gt; Total count of users visiting a site. Includes multiple visits by the same person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cachebuster&lt;/em&gt; To avoid the browser caching an old ad, the source code is modified by adding a unique number for each site visit, to "bust the cache" so that the new ad is actually served.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;DMA (Designated Market Area)&lt;/em&gt; The actual geographic region that an advertiser wants to advertise in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flight&lt;/em&gt; How long the ads will run for, a time measurement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frequency Cap&lt;/em&gt; The max number of times an ad can be shown to a unique user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geo-targeting&lt;/em&gt; Seems similar to DMA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invocation code&lt;/em&gt; I think this may be synonymous with Ad Tag. Refers to the code placed on a website that "summons" an ad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Line Item&lt;/em&gt; A single unit of advertising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Order&lt;/em&gt; A group of line items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roadblock (Takeover)&lt;/em&gt; When an advertiser takes over ever available ad spot on a page, this is called a RoadBlock or Takeover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ROS (Run of Site)&lt;/em&gt; Not sure about this definition. Seems to mean that you indicate a site to have your ads run on (such as google.com).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;SOV (Share of Voice)&lt;/em&gt; The percentage of a particular advertisers inventory that an advertiser owns during a campaign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="adtech"></category></entry><entry><title>Doing Haskel Tutorial</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/haskell.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2015-04-22:/haskell.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just some from the first chapter of the online version of &lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/"&gt;Learn you a Haskell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1 Starting Out&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/starting-out"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make prompt prettier using &lt;code&gt;:set prompt "ghci&amp;gt; "&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;50 * -1&lt;/code&gt; is an error, must do `50 * (-1)'. It seems to me that this is something to do with how whatever Haskell equivalent …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just some from the first chapter of the online version of &lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/"&gt;Learn you a Haskell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1 Starting Out&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/starting-out"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make prompt prettier using &lt;code&gt;:set prompt "ghci&amp;gt; "&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;50 * -1&lt;/code&gt; is an error, must do `50 * (-1)'. It seems to me that this is something to do with how whatever Haskell equivalent of operators is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ok, so * is a function, whose arguments are but between it, its an &lt;em&gt;infix&lt;/em&gt; function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;functions are called by writing name, space, arguments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parentheses are only used to group expressions into an argument.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; is used to define functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:l&lt;/code&gt; for load to load a &lt;code&gt;.hs&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;function names cannot begin with capital letters, the character `` is ok in a function name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to define a list, use the keyword &lt;code&gt;let&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;index a list usin &lt;code&gt;!!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add to end of list with &lt;code&gt;++&lt;/code&gt; add to begining with &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt;, note that adding to end is slow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ranges done using the &lt;code&gt;..&lt;/code&gt;, i.e. &lt;code&gt;[1..20]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tuples are defined using parentheses, however they are of fixed size but can contain mixed types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list comprehensions are awesome. The &lt;code&gt;|&lt;/code&gt; defines the predicates and domains , the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/code&gt; assigns sets to a variable, and commas separate the conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="programming"></category></entry></feed>