<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>John's Notes - business</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/feeds/business.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://notes.johnvial.info/</id><updated>2017-05-30T00:00:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>RedRock Cafe</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/redrock-cafe.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-30T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-30T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-30:/redrock-cafe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On an unimposing corner, only 5 minutes walk from the Mountain View
Caltrain station stands the RedRock cafe. Wooden finishings and
liberal lick of red point is the theme. The coffee is good (by my
Australian standards too!) but the best thing is the conversations
that you overhear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind me …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On an unimposing corner, only 5 minutes walk from the Mountain View
Caltrain station stands the RedRock cafe. Wooden finishings and
liberal lick of red point is the theme. The coffee is good (by my
Australian standards too!) but the best thing is the conversations
that you overhear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind me a young lady tries to convince her older co-founder or
possible investor that her startup is "just like Apple", and that if a
VC doesn't want to partner with them, then they probably just don't
get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next to me two co-founders are consoling each other to keep going:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't matter if they say that the problem may be too broad, as
 long as our assumptions are still correct there MUST be a market
 for it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a very out of character way, an older person is complaining about
how crap it is that his fridge is rusty. Ahh, rusty fridges, a
universal problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An older man appears to hold a phone interview at a nearby table. But
instead of asking technical questions seems to be judging his prospective
new hire by the age of his laptop. He also dismisses Apple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people think they [Apple] are innovative, and that they like to be
deliberate with their hardware, and that's why they don't always have the
latest ports. I just think they are lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, the Apple man decides to leave, citing that the cafe is not
that private. He is quickly replaced by two gents who unroll a Chess
board, and sit down with steaming tea. They speak in hushed tones as
they get ready to do battle, placing each piece down with a satisfying
knock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly my ears pick up, the lady behind me has just asked her friend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, &lt;pause&gt; I need you to write me a check!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a confident tone, the her friend replies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ofcourse I'll write you a check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in that same conversation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guy: It's really hard going after the consumers. You're not Apple.
Girl: But somebody has to go after the consumers! Bose, Bose just
bought it.
... see that's the problem, I care, I care about people. If I sell
the company and somebody buys it ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Girl: Is that REALLY true or are you just saying that to be positive?
Well, I'm glad it's happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they get up and leave the coffee shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Random comments from another table:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They added psuedo-random bubbles into the pipeline. I'm pretty sure
it's patented.
...
I spent most of my time fighting internal, I'm never doing that again.
...
People are gonna fight for resources...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Getting a 10x</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/getting-a-10x.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-08T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-08:/getting-a-10x.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What approach links Jeremy Howard and Elon Musk? I recently watched Elon's &lt;a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/elon_musk_the_future_we_re_building_and_boring"&gt;interview on TEDx&lt;/a&gt;, and I've also been watching Part 2 of the Fast.AI course by Jeremy Howard, in particular, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gfhLSTkRZLI&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;lesson 9&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elon was talking about building a 10x solution to boring machines. He broke it down into …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What approach links Jeremy Howard and Elon Musk? I recently watched Elon's &lt;a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/elon_musk_the_future_we_re_building_and_boring"&gt;interview on TEDx&lt;/a&gt;, and I've also been watching Part 2 of the Fast.AI course by Jeremy Howard, in particular, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gfhLSTkRZLI&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;lesson 9&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elon was talking about building a 10x solution to boring machines. He broke it down into sub components, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boring at the front and reinforcing at the back can give a 2x speed up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of boring is proportional to the diameter of the hole, by halving the diameter we can get a 4x cost reduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By using the machine closer to it's thermal and energy limit we can get another 1.5x.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elon, then multiplied these (2x4x1.5) and claimed that it was
approximately a 10x speed improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeremy also performed a similar calculation, but instead of 10x'ing a business, he was 10x'ing computation speed. Jeremy's logic was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can use SIMD to get a 6x speed up for computation that has been
  optimized to use the SIMD instructions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can use Parallel processing to usally get 2-4x speed up on a standard computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeremy then claims that you can add these (6 + 4) to get a roughly 10x speed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's interesting that they disagree on how to combine the
improvement. However, they both follow a similar logical path. I think
that this is a good way to build up a 10x advantage where no
single technology can get you there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I think that you should add you multiplicatives, not multiply them, see standard algebra.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>