<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>John's Notes - misc</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/feeds/misc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://notes.johnvial.info/</id><updated>2017-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Digital Advertising Glossary</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/digital-advertising-glossary.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-05-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2017-05-01:/digital-advertising-glossary.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are trying to understand the advertising world, the following
link helped me. &lt;a href="http://studybreakmedia.com/glossary"&gt;Advertising Glossary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've typed out many of the terms to help me remember them. Perhaps it will help you as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Tag&lt;/em&gt; Javascript that coordinates serving of ads to the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Network&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Auction …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are trying to understand the advertising world, the following
link helped me. &lt;a href="http://studybreakmedia.com/glossary"&gt;Advertising Glossary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've typed out many of the terms to help me remember them. Perhaps it will help you as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Tag&lt;/em&gt; Javascript that coordinates serving of ads to the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Network&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Auction Price Floor&lt;/em&gt;. I've understood that ad spots were an auction, I always thought it was one of those strange auctions that benefit the seller the most. I think it was called a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dutch_auction"&gt;Dutch Auction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creative&lt;/em&gt; Refers to a piece of work (graphic or text) that is created, I also think it could mean a person who creates that work too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Daisy chain (Ad Chain)&lt;/em&gt; This term seems confusing even after having read the description. The description describes arranging ads by price, but why call it a daisy chain??&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discrepancy&lt;/em&gt; Another confusing term, I think it means the difference between the clients (viewers) and ad partners (people with ads to serve).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;DSP&lt;/em&gt; Not Digital Signal Processing, but instead Demand Side Platform, apparently a marketplace to sell ad &lt;em&gt;inventory&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;IAB&lt;/em&gt; Interactive Advertising Bureau. I guess this is a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peak_organisation"&gt;Peak Body&lt;/a&gt; for advertising industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Passback Tag&lt;/em&gt; Apparently an ad partner can choose to pass on the opportunity to serve an ad. I wonder if they still pay for the space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revenue Share Model&lt;/em&gt; Describes how much of the advertising revenue the publisher gets vs the ad provider. (The publisher is some website, the provider is an exchange like Google's Ad Exchange).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;RTB (Real Time Bidding)&lt;/em&gt; Allows advertisers to bid on ad slots in real time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;SSP (Supply Side Platform)&lt;/em&gt; Allows publishers to sell their websites inventory to sell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;View-ability&lt;/em&gt; A "new" metric, will be true if 50% of ads are displayed for atleast 1 second. I wonder how much of a problem very quickly displayed ads were for this metric to be introduced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Volume&lt;/em&gt; How many impressions or pageviews a website receives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPA (Cost Per Action)&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. the customer must take an action for the advertiser to get paid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPC (Cost Per Click)&lt;/em&gt; CPA where the action is a click.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;CPM (Cost Per Milli)&lt;/em&gt; Confusingly, this is per 1000 impressions, not 1e6 impressions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;eCPM (effective CPM)&lt;/em&gt; Tries to compensate for impressions that we're actually shown or paid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;rCPM (real CPM)&lt;/em&gt; A metric that takes into account the impressions that occurred. Apparently not all impressions are paid??&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ATF (Above The Fold)&lt;/em&gt;, i.e. the first part of the website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Units&lt;/em&gt; The space where an ad is displayed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Banner/Leader board, Rectangle, Tower/Skyscraper&lt;/em&gt; Terms to describe the shape of the ad unit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;BTF (Below The Fold)&lt;/em&gt; Opposite of ATF.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Native ads&lt;/em&gt; Advertising that blends into the user experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rich Media&lt;/em&gt; Apparently this is richer advertising, I'm not sure I've encountered these before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rising Stars&lt;/em&gt; A "more standardised" version of Rich Media.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Site Skin&lt;/em&gt; Creative that appears behind the main content of the page. I think I've seen &lt;a href="http://www.ebay.com"&gt;e-bay&lt;/a&gt; do that before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ad Impression&lt;/em&gt; A single ad view, can be purchased.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bounce Rate&lt;/em&gt; The percentage of users that click an ad but immediately leave the linked site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pageview&lt;/em&gt; whenever a user loads a page, a pageview occurs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Re-Targeting pixel&lt;/em&gt; A unique identifier that tracks user behaviour allowing targeted ads. It's weird that this is called a pixel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Visitor&lt;/em&gt; Total count of users visiting a site. Includes multiple visits by the same person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cachebuster&lt;/em&gt; To avoid the browser caching an old ad, the source code is modified by adding a unique number for each site visit, to "bust the cache" so that the new ad is actually served.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;DMA (Designated Market Area)&lt;/em&gt; The actual geographic region that an advertiser wants to advertise in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flight&lt;/em&gt; How long the ads will run for, a time measurement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frequency Cap&lt;/em&gt; The max number of times an ad can be shown to a unique user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Geo-targeting&lt;/em&gt; Seems similar to DMA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Invocation code&lt;/em&gt; I think this may be synonymous with Ad Tag. Refers to the code placed on a website that "summons" an ad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Line Item&lt;/em&gt; A single unit of advertising.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Order&lt;/em&gt; A group of line items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roadblock (Takeover)&lt;/em&gt; When an advertiser takes over ever available ad spot on a page, this is called a RoadBlock or Takeover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;ROS (Run of Site)&lt;/em&gt; Not sure about this definition. Seems to mean that you indicate a site to have your ads run on (such as google.com).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;SOV (Share of Voice)&lt;/em&gt; The percentage of a particular advertisers inventory that an advertiser owns during a campaign.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="adtech"></category></entry><entry><title>Doing Haskel Tutorial</title><link href="http://notes.johnvial.info/doing-haskel-tutorial.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>John Vial</name></author><id>tag:notes.johnvial.info,2015-04-22:/doing-haskel-tutorial.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just some from the first chapter of the online version of &lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/"&gt;Learn you a Haskell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1 Starting Out&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/starting-out"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make prompt prettier using &lt;code&gt;:set prompt "ghci&amp;gt; "&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;50 * -1&lt;/code&gt; is an error, must do `50 * (-1)'. It seems to me that this is something to do with how whatever Haskell equivalent …&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just some from the first chapter of the online version of &lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/"&gt;Learn you a Haskell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;1 Starting Out&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/starting-out"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make prompt prettier using &lt;code&gt;:set prompt "ghci&amp;gt; "&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;50 * -1&lt;/code&gt; is an error, must do `50 * (-1)'. It seems to me that this is something to do with how whatever Haskell equivalent of operators is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ok, so * is a function, whose arguments are but between it, its an &lt;em&gt;infix&lt;/em&gt; function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;functions are called by writing name, space, arguments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parentheses are only used to group expressions into an argument.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an &lt;code&gt;=&lt;/code&gt; is used to define functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;:l&lt;/code&gt; for load to load a &lt;code&gt;.hs&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;function names cannot begin with capital letters, the character `` is ok in a function name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to define a list, use the keyword &lt;code&gt;let&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;index a list usin &lt;code&gt;!!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add to end of list with &lt;code&gt;++&lt;/code&gt; add to begining with &lt;code&gt;:&lt;/code&gt;, note that adding to end is slow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ranges done using the &lt;code&gt;..&lt;/code&gt;, i.e. &lt;code&gt;[1..20]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tuples are defined using parentheses, however they are of fixed size but can contain mixed types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;list comprehensions are awesome. The &lt;code&gt;|&lt;/code&gt; defines the predicates and domains , the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/code&gt; assigns sets to a variable, and commas separate the conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry></feed>